So here we are in Google Colab for our first collaborative session on the cloud using a GPU box.
구글 Colab입니다 GPU 박스를 이용한 클라우드에서의 첫 협업 세션이죠
On that note, I've actually connected to a T4 box, one of the lower spec boxes.
T4 박스에 연결했습니다 하위 사양 중 하나죠
You can see my resources here.
여기 리소스가 보이시죠
You can see that I just ran this and managed to fill up most of the GPU, but then I've just gone to
이걸 실행하면 GPU 대부분을 채울 수 있죠 런타임으로 가서 재시작
runtime and done a restart session, which is why the GPU memory has come slamming down to nothing.
세션을 했어요 그래서 GPU 메모리가 아무것도 안 된 거죠
Anyway, we'll now, uh, remove this screen so that it's not in our way.
어쨌든 방해되지 않게 이 스크린을 제거할게요
There we go.
됐어요
Uh, and look at our colab.
콜랍 좀 보세요
So I begin by introducing you to the world of pipelines, a reminder that the Transformers library with
파이프라인의 세계로 시작하겠습니다 얼굴을 끌어안는 트랜스포머 라이브러리에
hugging face has these two API levels the pipelines.
파이프라인이라는 두 API 레벨이 있어요
And then later we will come to Tokenizers and models for today.
오늘의 토큰라이저와 모델에 관해선 나중에 얘기하죠
It's all about pipelines, high level API that allows you to run inference for common tasks in just
파이프라인에 관한 거죠 상위 레벨 API 말이에요 일반적인 작업에 대한 추론을 실행하게
a couple of lines of code, which makes it frictionless and easy to be using open source models in production.
합니다 코드 두어 줄로요 프로덕션에서 마찰 없이 오픈 소스 모델을 쉽게 사용하게 해주죠
The way that we use it is, as I say, super simple.
우리가 사용하는 방법은 아주 간단해요
You first call pipeline and you pass in a string with the task that you want to do.
파이프라인을 호출하고 문자열을 전달합니다 원하는 작업을 전달하죠
So there's various things you can pass in here, various, uh, strings, and you will see what they
여러분이 넘길 수 있는 다양한 것들이 있어요 다양한 문자열이죠 잠시 후에 그게 뭔지 보실
are in just a moment.
수 있어요
You get back a pipeline object and you can then call it with your input, and you get back the result.
파이프라인 객체를 얻어서 입력으로 호출할 수 있고 get 결과도 얻을 수 있죠
That's all there is to it.
그게 다예요
Simple as that.
간단해요
So I'm going to start by doing the installs the Transformers library of course, which is the heart
트랜스포머 라이브러리 설치부터 시작할게요 모든 것의 핵심이죠
Datasets is a library that gives us access to hugging faces, datasets.
데이터셋은 얼굴을 포옹하는 데이터셋 라이브러리예요
Diffusers actually are sort of companion library to transformers when you're talking about diffusion
디퓨저는 트랜스포머의 동반 라이브러리 같은 거예요 이미지를 만들어내는 디퓨전
models that generate images.
모델 말이에요
Often when I say transformers, I'm really referring to both transformers and its sibling library diffusers
트랜스포머라고 하면 트랜스포머와 형제 라이브러리 디퓨저를 말하는 거예요
as well for any times that we're generating images.
이미지를 만들 때 쓰는 거죠
So I'm doing a pip install.
파이프를 설치하고 있어요
When you have an exclamation mark like that in front of a of a cell, it means that you want to run
a 셀 앞에 저런 느낌표가 있으면 터미널 명령으로 실행하고 싶다는
that as a terminal command.
뜻이에요
And so that's going to run.
실행될 거예요
And if you didn't know that minus Q is it puts it on quiet mode so that we don't get all of the outputs
이 마이너스 Q를 모르신다면 침묵 모드로 설정합니다. 모든 패키지를 설치하는 출력을 얻지 않기 위해서입니다. 하지만 지금은
of installing all of the packages, but it installs now installed particularly quickly for me because
설치가 빠르게 이루어지고 있습니다. 왜냐하면 아까 이 노트북을 실행해
I already ran this notebook earlier.
봤기 때문이죠.
It may take 30s for you while those packages install.
패키지가 설치되는 동안 30이 걸릴 수도 있어요
And then we're going to do some imports.
그런 다음 수입을 할 거예요
And then once we've done that we're going to get started with pipelines.
Get을 완료하고 나면 파이프라인으로 넘어가죠
Get ready for this.
Get it, Get it 준비하세요
So first of all sentiment analysis is something positive or negative a bit of text.
먼저 감정 분석은 긍정적이거나 부정적인 비트예요
And we're going to start by saying I am super excited to be on the way to LM mastery.
이 말부터 할게요 LM 마스터로 가는 길에 들어서 정말 신나요
I wonder if that's positive or negative.
좋은 건지 나쁜 건지 모르겠네요
So a few things to note immediately.
몇 가지 주의할 점이 있어요
First of all, it warns us that no model was supplied and it's defaulted to this particular model.
먼저, 어떤 모델도 제공되지 않았고 기본값이 이 모델에 있다고 경고하네요
What it means there is that you can say model equals and tell it which of the models from the hugging
무슨 뜻이냐면 모델 =이라고 입력하면 안는 얼굴 허브에서 어떤 모델을 이 파이프라인의
face hub you would like to use as part of this pipeline.
일부로 사용할 건지 정할 수 있다는 거죠
If you don't supply one, it just picks the default for that task, which is great for our purposes
하나를 제공하지 않으면 해당 작업에 대한 기본값을 선택합니다 오늘 우리 목적에 아주
today.
유용하죠
The other thing it's telling us is that the GPU is available in the environment, but we didn't tell
또 다른 건 환경에서 GPU가 사용 가능하지만 GPU를 사용하라고 하진 않았다는
it to use a GPU, which it correctly thinks is a bit strange of us.
겁니다 비트는 우리가 좀 이상하다고 생각하죠
And we can make it do that by saying device equals Cuda like that, and that command will tell it that
장치가 CUDOW와 같다고 하면 그렇게 할 수 있어요 그럼 그 명령은 이 파이프라인을 사용하고
we would like to use this pipeline, and we would like to take advantage of the GPU that we have.
싶다고 하죠 우리가 가진 GPU 덕을 보고 싶다고요
And so now we've run it, it's run on our GPU.
이제 실행했어요 GPU 상에서 실행됐죠
And maybe we should also look at the results.
결과도 살펴보는 게 좋겠어요
The result is that it's considered a positive statement and its score, which is its level of confidence,
긍정적인 성명서로 간주되고 있습니다 점수인 자신감 수준도
is very high indeed.
매우 높고요
So that sounds good.
좋은 것 같아요
I think that's probably a good interpretation of the sentence.
그 문장을 잘 해석한 것 같아요
Let's just try putting in the word not.
안 된다고만 해두죠
I'm not super excited to be on the way to LLM mastery.
LLM 마스터가 되는 게 썩 기쁘진 않아요
Perish the thought.
그럴 리가요
I hope you're not thinking that for a moment, but we should just check that.
그런 생각은 안 하셨으면 좋겠는데 확인해 보죠
If we say that, it clearly identifies, then that the label is negative and it's pretty confident that
우리가 그렇게 말하면 라벨이 부정적이라는 걸 확실히 인식하고 부정적
that is indeed a negative statement to be making.
선언이라는 걸 확신할 수 있죠
So that works well, let's leave it on an enthusiastic note.
잘 작동하네요 열정적으로 마무리하죠
We would want it to think otherwise.
그렇게 생각하길 바라죠
Named entity recognition is the next task.
독립체 인식이 다음 작업이죠
I'm just going to be rattling through these pipelines and you should try all of this yourself.
난 파이프라인이나 통과할 테니 당신도 직접 해 봐요
Of course, named entity recognition is when you provide some text and you ask the model to identify
물론 엔터티 인지션은 여러분이 텍스트를 제공하고 모델에게 어떤 종류의
what kinds of things are being referred to.
것이 참조되는지 확인하는 거죠
This is a standard one that that I took.
이건 제가 찍은 표준 사진이에요
Barack Obama was the 44th president of the United States.
버락 오바마는 미국의 44대 대통령이었죠
Uh, and we ask it to analyze that, And it responds here that the there's it responds with, um, two
분석을 요청하면 여기에 반응을 해요 두 가지 다른 이름으로
different named entities.
응답하죠
If you can see it in this text right here, the first named entity is of type per as in person.
여기 이 텍스트를 보시면 첫 번째 명명된 엔터티의 형식은 사람 이름 당 퍼예요
Uh, it's got high confidence and the word is Barack Obama.
자신감이 넘치고 이름은 버락 오바마예요
And the second one is a lock for a location and the word is United States.
두 번째는 장소 이름인데 미국이라는 뜻이에요
And of course, it shows you tells you where that is in the input.
입력에서 어디에 있는지 알려주는 거죠
It's a very common use case in data science, a great thing to have at your disposal and to be able
데이터 과학에서는 아주 흔한 사용 사례입니다 원하는 대로 빨리 할 수
to do so quickly.
있으면 좋죠
Question answering with context, you can create a question answering pipeline.
컨텍스트를 이용한 질문 답변 파이프라인을 만들 수 있어요
And again, I'm using this device's Cuda to run it on the GPU and say, who was the 44th president of
다시 한 번 이 장치의 CUDU를 이용해 GPU에서 실행하고 누가 미국의 44대 대통령이었는지
the US and provide it with some context here.
컨텍스트를 제공한다고 하죠
So it has something to look up against and ask it to print the result there, and it's simply no surprise
검색할 게 있고 결과를 프린트하도록 요청하는데 결과에 대한 놀라운
answers that result.
답변이 없어요
I think.
아마도요
I'm not trying to show off the power of this model right now.
이 모델의 힘을 과시하려는 게 아니에요
I'm trying to show off the simplicity of the pipeline API.
파이프라인 API의 단순함을 보여주려는 거예요
You can play with more sophisticated context and better questions, and I'd also encourage you to try
더 정교한 컨텍스트와 더 나은 질문을 가지고 놀 수 있습니다 다양한 모델을 통과시켜
passing in different models to explore some of the different models available on the Hugging Face hub.
보는 것도 추천합니다 페이스 허브에서 이용 가능한 다양한 모델을 탐구해 보세요
Text summarization is just as easy.
텍스트 요약도 간단해요
You then of course the pipeline.
파이프라인도 빼놓을 수 없죠
The type is summarization and you can put in a ton of text.
유형은 요약이고 많은 텍스트를 쓸 수 있어요. Tool karaoke Tool karaoke.
Here I'm talking about I'm generally gushing about the hugging face Transformers library.
포옹하는 트랜스포머 라이브러리 얘기를 하고 있네요
I ask for the summarizer, I give it a min and a max length, and I get back a nice short and sharp
요약본을 요청하고 짧은 시간 동안 최대 길이로 말하면 get 절차가 짧고
sentence that summarizes that text.
명료한 문장으로 돌아오죠
Um, and I think it's mostly just a sort of chop of what I already put in.
이미 넣은 걸 토막 내서 얹은 거예요
So it didn't do a wonderful job, but it's a pretty simple model.
잘 만들진 못했지만 단순한 모형이었어요
Again, you can explore better summarizations from better models.
더 나은 모델에서 더 나은 요약본을 탐구할 수 있어요
When you have a moment, we can translate.
시간 되시면 통역해 드릴게요
Translation on to English.
영어로 번역해 주세요
To French.
프랑스어로요
The data scientists were truly amazed by the power and simplicity of the hugging Face pipeline API.
데이터 과학자들은 어징 페이스 파이프라인 API의 힘과 단순함에 정말 놀랐죠
And let's see how it performs for all of you French speakers out there.
프랑스어를 구사하는 모든 분께 어떻게 작동하는지 보죠
I'm not going to try and say that my high school French is good enough, but you can say, astonished
고등학교 때 배운 프랑스어가 뛰어나다는 말은 안 하겠지만 허징 페이스 파이프라인의
at the power and simplicity of the API of the hugging face pipeline.
강력하고 단순한 API에 놀랐다고는 말해 줄 수 있죠
And as far as my limited French skills can tell, that seems like it's a pretty robust translation.
제 프랑스어 실력으로는 꽤 확실한 번역인 것 같네요
Very easy classification, or what's called zero shot classification, when we just give it an example
아주 쉬운 분류, 혹은 제로 샷 분류라 불리는 건 그냥 예만 주고 일부
and ask it to label it with some labels without giving it any prior examples.
라벨을 붙이라고 할 때죠 이전 예는 주지 않고요
So we're giving it the text hugging face Transformers library is amazing, and asking it to classify
그래서 얼굴 껴안기 트랜스포머 라이브러리는 굉장하다고 표현하고 기술, 스포츠,
technology or sports or politics.
정치 등으로 분류하라고 했어요
And let's see how it performs.
어떻게 작동하는지 보죠
Um, and it says labels, uh, for technology.
기술 라벨이라고 적혀 있어요
It gives it a score of 95% and then a tiny score for sports and politics.
95%의 점수를 받았지만 스포츠와 정치학에서는 아주 낮은 점수를 받았죠
Politics.
정치요
Low of them all.
가장 낮은 수치죠
Uh, and that seems especially as we didn't particularly have any words that were directly tech related.
특히나 기술과 직접적으로 관련된 단어가 없었으니까요
That's not bad at all.
나쁘지 않네요
And then last on this series of the really simple ones is text generation.
마지막으로 이 시리즈의 정말 간단한 건 텍스트 생성이에요
Let's say if there's one thing I want you to remember about using Huggingface pipelines, it's and let's
H깅페이스 파이프라인을 사용할 때 기억해야 할 게 하나 있다면 그건∙∙∙ 어디 보죠
see.
바닐라 모델을 사용하고 있지만 어떻게 처리하는지 보죠
It's that any application that runs on Nautilus will generate the hugging face package as the target,
노틸러스호에서 실행되는 모든 응용 프로그램은 컴파일된 것처럼 안는 얼굴 패키지를
just as if it had been compiled.
목표로 하죠
So that's a bit random.
비트가 좀 뜬금없죠
It did better in some of my, uh, uh, prior tests.
전에 했던 검사에서는 결과가 더 좋았어요
Uh, it's how good and resilient they are.
얼마나 잘 회복하는지가 중요하죠
As with any project, you'll need to remember your risk tolerance.
모든 프로젝트가 그렇듯 위험 부담을 감수해야 해요
Remember when to push it to the point.
언제 끝까지 밀어붙여야 하는지 기억하세요
So of course, it's rambling based on how it thinks that begins.
어떻게 시작됐는지에 따라 횡설수설하는 거죠
You can try some more amusing starts and see how it performs.
좀 더 재미있는 시작을 해보고 어떻게 되는지 보세요
You could also try bigger, beefier models and you'll get something.
좀 더 크고 육중한 모델도 시도해 볼 수 있어요 get it get it get it get it get it get it
Of course, that is more accurate in terms of the text generation.
물론 텍스트 생성에 있어서는 그게 더 정확하죠
Okay.
네
And then of course, since you are now all experts in Multi-modality, let's just show you some image
이제 여러분은 다중 양식의 전문가들이니 이미지 생성을 보여드리죠
Everything up to this point has been using the Transformers library, and we're now flipping to the
지금까지는 트랜스포머 라이브러리를 사용했고 디퓨전 스타일
diffusers or diffusion style models, which is the architecture that generates images.
모델로 영상을 전송하고 있어요 이미지를 생성하는 아키텍처죠
And we are using the well-known stable diffusion model, the parameters a few more need to be passed
잘 알려진 안정적 확산 모델을 사용하고 있는데 몇 가지 변수를 더 통과시켜야 해요
in.
곧 보시게 될 거예요
We need to tell it the kind of data type that we're using.
우리가 사용하는 데이터 타입을 알려줘야 해요
And then once we've done that and and put it on the GPU, we can give it some text.
그 작업을 마치고 GPU 위에 얹으면 텍스트를 줄 수 있어요
And I'm saying here a class of data scientists learning about AI in the surreal style of Salvador Dali,
살바도르 달리의 초현실적인 스타일로 인공지능을 연구하는 데이터 과학자들이죠
and let's generate that image.
그 이미지를 생성해보죠
This will take a little bit longer.
이 비트는 시간이 좀 더 걸릴 거예요
It's a bit more of a meaty task.
좀 더 비트 있는 작업이죠
Um, it might take even longer for you because I have the benefit of having already run this once.
당신은 더 오래 걸릴 수도 있어요 저는 이미 한 번 실행해봤으니까요
And so the model has been downloaded from Huggingface and stored in its local directory.
H깅페이스에서 모델을 다운로드해 로컬 디렉터리에 저장했어요
So it may take more like a minute when you run it.
실행하는 데 1분 정도 걸릴 수도 있어요
Um, but here we go.
하지만 시작할게요
Here are here is the room full of, uh, uh, class of data scientists learning about AI in the surreal
이 방에는 데이터 과학자들이 가득합니다 달리의 초현실적인 스타일로 인공지능을 배우고
style of Dali.
있죠
I love it, I love it.
정말 좋아요
Do you look anything like these guys?
이 사람들과 닮았어요?
Uh, I hope not only in your worst nightmare, but there we go.
최악의 악몽에서만 그러는 게 아니라 저기도 그랬으면 좋겠네요
This is the surreal Dali.
초현실적인 달리예요
Scary, strange world.
무섭고 이상한 세상이죠
Uh, for a class of data scientists, I love it.
데이터 과학자치고 정말 마음에 들어요
Now, you can substitute this for the flux model that I mentioned before, and you may remember, I
이걸 플럭스 모델로 대체할 수 있어요 아까 강의에서
flashed up the code at the last, uh, lectures.
코드를 보여드렸죠
Uh, by all means, use that.
네, 그렇게 하세요
You'll find it does take longer, and you will need to be running on a beefier box than the T4.
시간이 더 오래 걸리고 T4보다 더 우람한 박스로 달려야 해요
If you do it on an A100, it'll take a couple of minutes and you will get a breathtakingly good image
A100 카메라로 하면 몇 분이면 숨이 멎을 정도로 멋진 이미지가 완성되죠
like the one that I showed in the last lecture.
지난 강의에서 보여 드린 것처럼요
Uh, but, um, this seems pretty good for a quick, cheap model to me.
하지만 저렴한 초고속 모델치고는 괜찮은 것 같아요
And last but not least, some audio generation.
마지막으로 오디오 세대예요
Uh, we are going to use the text to speech pipeline now, and we are going to tell it which model we
텍스트-언어 파이프라인을 사용할 겁니다 어떤 모델을 원하는지 알려주는 거죠
want.
마이크로소프트의 스피치 5 TTS를 원하죠
There is a little bit more that you have to provide into the model, something about the type of voice
모델에 제공해야 할 게 좀 더 있어요 비트가 사용해야 할 음성의 종류
that it should use.
같은 거요
And so there's a couple of lines to load that data set from hugging face.
얼굴을 안는 것으로 데이터 세트를 로드하는 라인이 몇 개 있어요
Um, and, and get it into the right shape.
Get it으로 모양을 잡아야죠
But once you've done that, we can just call our pipeline and we're going to say hi to an artificial
다 됐으면 파이프라인을 호출하고 인공 지능 엔지니어에게
intelligence engineer on the way to mastery and pass in this this speech voice.
인사한 다음 이 음성 메시지를 전달할게요
Um, then this is some code to then, uh, write that to, uh, to a wav file.
이건 웨이브 파일에 쓸 코드예요
Um, and uh, we will then be able to play it within the, um, this, uh, Colab notebook.
이 콜랍 공책에 그 내용을 담을 거예요
So it ran pretty fast.
꽤 빨랐어요
Let's see how it sounds.
소리가 어떤지 들어보죠
Hi.
안녕하세요
To an artificial intelligence engineer on the way to mastery.
숙련된 인공지능 엔지니어에게요
Seems pretty good to me.
괜찮은 것 같은데요
That would be an example of using pipeline for text to speech generation.
텍스트에서 음성 생성 파이프라인을 사용하는 예가 되겠네요
And that wraps up this colab walkthrough of pipeline APIs.
파이프라인 API의 Colab 워크스루가 끝났네요
I, of course, will share this colab so that you can have access to this and very much encourage you
물론 이 Colab을 공유할 테니 여러분이 액세스할 수 있고 직접 시도해
to go through and try these yourself, experiment with different inputs and also experiment with different
보시길 권장합니다 여러 입력값을 실험하고 H깅페이스 허브에서 찾을
models that you'll find on the Huggingface hub.
수 있는 여러 모델도 실험해 보세요
Enjoy.
맛있게 드세요